Guide to the Murrysville Garden Club Records, 1952-2016 AIS.2016.05
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Awards & Scholarships, VI.
  - Awards Recieved, 1.
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs National Kellogg Medal for Civic Achievement, 1995 (Box 6a, Folder 3)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Outstanding Achievement Award, 1995 (Box 6a, Folder 4)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Outstanding Educational Exhibit, 1997 (Box 6a, Folder 4b)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Publicity Press Book Award, 1995-1997 (Box 6a, Folder 5)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Purple Rosette Award, 1982 (Box 6a, Folder 6)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Purple Rosette Award, 1987 (Box 6a, Folder 7)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Red and Green Rosette Award, 1985 (Box 6a, Folder 8)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Smokey Bear - Woodsy Owl Poster Contest Award for Sponsoring a National Finalist, 1999 (Box 6a, Folder 9)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Special Achievement Certificate, 1993-1997 (Box 6a, Folder 10-13)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Yearbook Certificate of Merit, 1995-1997 (Box 6a, Folder 14)
    - National Disaster Fund Certificate of Award, 1998 (Box 6a, Folder 15)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Certificate of Appreciation, Undated (Box 6a, Folder 16)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Civic Development or Improvement Award, 2001 (Box 6a, Folder 17)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Environmental Concern Award, 2004-2008 (Box 6a, Folder 18)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Horticulture Therapy Award, 2005 (Box 6a, Folder 19)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Increase in Membership Awards, 2004-2007 (Box 6a, Folder 20)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Member Award of Honor, 2004 (Box 6a, Folder 21)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Publications Award, 2004 (Box 6a, Folder 22)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Table Artistry Award, 2007 (Box 6a, Folder 23)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Tommy Donnan Certificate of Merit, 2011 (Box 6a, Folder 24)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Yearbook Award, 2002-2006 (Box 6a, Folder 25)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated and Garden Club Federaton of Pennsylvania Certificate of Participation in the Patriotic Tree Planting Project, 2007 (Box 6a, Folder 26)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated and Shell Corporation Freedom Trees Award, c. 2001-2003 (Box 6a, Folder 27)
    - Pennsylvania Horticultural Society Community Greening Award, 1997 (Box 6a, Folder 28)
    - Signage from Shows, 1993-1995 (Box 6a, Folder 29)
    - Signage from Shows, undated (Map-case 32-1, Oversize 1)
    - William Penn Care Center Certificate of Recognition, 1996 (Map-case 32-1, Folder 29b)
    - Awards & Certificates Scrapbook, 1960-1999 (Map-case 32-1, Folder 29c-29e)
  - Awards & Scholarships Presented by the Club, 2.
    This subseries consists of awards and scholarships given by the MGC to other entities. Included in this section are the student scholarships which the Club offers to college students studying areas related to gardening and the Business Beautification Award for Murrysville businesses which maintain their properties in an appealing way. The records in this section are comprised of scrapbooks, official awards, and award applications. The material dates from 1972-2014. The folders are organized thematically.
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Financial Aid and Scholarships, 1993-2011 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Business Beautification Award, 1972-1999 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Business Beautification Award, 2000-2014 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Betty Yant Scholarship Fund, Undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Scholarships, 1993; 2001-2011 (Box 6, Folder 34-43)
    - Valerie and Dottie Award for Service to the Garden Club, 2012-2013 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Murrysville Garden Club and Franklin Regional School District Martha Miller Hummingbird Award, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Murrysville Garden Club, National Council of State Garden Clubs, and Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Speech and Essay Contests, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Financial Aid and Scholarships, 1999-2002 (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Events & Projects, VII.
  This series is composed of all material related to projects, events, and activities organized by the MGC. A substantial part of the records relate to the MGC's Christmas Workshop, Flower Shows, and Garden Tours. The records consist of both scrapbooks and individual items within folders. The material dates from 1952-2015. The folders are organized alphabetically and then chronologically.
  - Activity Summary, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Annual Presidents Tea, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Art Auction, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Butterfly Habitat and Garden Project, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Christmas House Tour, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Christmas Party, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Christmas Workshop, 1984-1992 (Box 6, Folder 54-61)
  - Communities Incorporated Park Project, 1953-1958 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Cotter's Corner Project, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Duff Park Project, 1968-1970 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Flower Show, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Flower Show, 1999 (Box 6b, Folder 66)
  - Flower Show Guestbook, 1981 (Box 6b, Folder 67)
  - Flower Show Handbook (National Garden Club, inc.), 2007 (Box 6b, Folder 66b)
  - Franklin Regional School District Projects, 1972-1983 (Box 6b, Folder 68)
  - Franklin Regional School District Projects, 1997-2000 (Box 6b, Folder 69)
  - Garden Tour, 1998 (Box 6b, Folder 70)
  - Garden Tour, 2000 (Box 6b, Folder 71)
  - Garden Tour (Part I of II), 2002 (Box 6b, Folder 72)
  - Garden Tour (Part II of II), 2002 (Box 6b, Folder 73)
  - Garden Tour, 2004 (Box 6b, Folder 74)
  - Garden Tour, 2012 (Box 6b, Folder 75)
  - Greensburg May Sale Records, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Greensburg May Sale Records, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Home for the Holidays Event, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Johnny Appleseed Planting Project, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Murrysville Community Day, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Plant-In Event, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Plant Sale, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Project and Activities Summary Scrapbook, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Puketos Garden Club 70th Anniversary Celebration, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Red Bud Plant-In Event, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Route 22 Beautification Project, 2005-2015 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Tots and Toddlers Garden, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Tour of Children's School Gardens, Undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Clippings, VIII.
  This series is composed of newspaper and magazine clippings collected by the Club. These include stories covering MGC and Junior Garden Club events and the "Green Thumb" column published by members of the Club. The material dates from 1959-2016. The folders are organized alphabetically and then chronologically.
  - General Clippings, 1959-2016 (Box 7, Folder 14-30)
  - Green Thumb Newspaper Column and Related Clippings, 1976-2010 (Box 7, Folder 31-35)
- Junior Garden Club Earth Team, IX.
  This series collates the records of the Murrysville Junior Garden Club Earth Team. The Junior Garden Club Earth Team is open to Murrysville area elementary and middle school students and is sponsored by the MGC. The purpose of the Team is to teach the community's youth the value of environmentalism. The series is composed of four subseries. The material dates from 1968-2012.
  - Junior Garden Club Yearbooks, 1.
    This subseries is composed of the yearbooks of the Junior Garden Club Earth Team. Like the yearbooks of the MGC, those of the Junior Garden Club Earth Team typically include an overview of activities undertaken in the past year, a list of officers, a list of awards won in the past year, and updates on ongoing projects. The material in this subseries has substantial gaps and includes only the years 1968, 1972, and 1985. The folders are organized chronologically.
    - Yearbook, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Yearbook, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Yearbook, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Junior Garden Club Committee Reports and Financial Records, 2.
    This subseries consists of the financial records, annual reports, and committee descriptions of the Junior Garden Club Earth Team. These records detail the income and expenditure of the Team, summaries of projects, and the activity and membership of the Team's governing committees. The material dates from 1987-2012, with the years 1994-1995 not included. The folders are organized thematically.
    - Annual Reports, 1987-1993 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Annual Reports, 1996-1999 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Annual Reports, 2000-2005 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Annual Reports, 2006-2009 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Annual Reports, 2010-2012 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Committee Descriptions, Undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Junior Garden Club Projects, 3.
    This subseries consists of summaries of the Junior Garden Club Earth Team's projects in the community. The material dates from 2001-2005. The folders are organized alphabetically and then chronologically.
    - Project Overviews, 2003-2005 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Today's Youth Plant Tomorrow's Trees Project, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Today's Youth Plant Tomorrow's Trees Project, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Awards Won by the Junior Garden Club, 4.
    This subseries collates all of the awards and forms of recognition given to the Junior Garden Club Earth Team. The bulk of the material consists of awards given to the Team by the Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania (GCFP), National Council of State Garden Clubs (NCSGC), and National Garden Clubs Incorporated (NGC). The records include scrapbooks, official awards, and award applications. The material dates from 1975-2011. The folders are organized alphabetically and the chronologically.
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Conservation Achievement Award, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Junior Flower Show Orange Ribbon Award, 1988-1995 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Junior Garden Club Award, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Junior Garden Club Leadership Award, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Junior Garden Club Leadership Award, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Junior Garden Club Staging Award, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Junior Gardener Trophy, 1988-2007 (Box 7, Folder 54-57)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Junior and/or Intermediate Horticulture Achievement Award, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Junior Yearbook Award, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Youth Flower Show Schedule Award, 1999-2005 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Youth Horticulture Award, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Youth Standard Flower Show Award, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Youth Superior Flower Show Award, 2002-2003 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Youth Yearbook Award, 1996-2009 (Box 7, Folder 64-66)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Augusta H. Brewer Certificate of Merit, 1990-1994 (Box 7, Folder 67-69)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Augusta H. Brewer Certificate of Merit, 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Civic Development or Improvement Award, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Helen Hussey Champlin Award of $50, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Junior and Intermediate Flower Show, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Red Rosette Award, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs Van Blanchard Flower Show Achievement Award, 1994-1999 (Box 8, Folder 8-11)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Hessie Thomson Morrah Award for Horticultural Achievement, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Hessie Thomsn Morrah Award for Horticultural Achievement, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Junior Leadership Award, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Junior and/or Intermediate Garden Club Award, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Red Rosette Award, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Van Blanchard Flower Show Achievement Award, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Youth Horticulture Education Award, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - National Garden Clubs Incorporated Youth Standard Flower Show Award, 2003-2005 (Box 8, Folder 19-21)
- Correspondence, X.
  This series consists of all correspondence (letters, postcards, emails, greeting cards, etc.) in the records of the Club that were not preserved with other documents. The material dates from 1988-2011.
  - Correspondence, 1988-2011 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Photographs, XI.
  This series consists of all photographs in the collection not included in scrapbooks. There is a significant variety in the format of material in the series, including standard photographic negatives, slide negatives, Polaroids, and varying sizes of normal photographs. The material dates from 1952-2016. The folders are organized alphabetically and then chronologically.
  - April Program, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - August Meeting, Undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Betty Manayek Speaking at School, c. 2000s (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - B.G. Garden Planning and Construction, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Biblical Garden Walk, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Birthday Party, Undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Business Beautification, 2005-2007 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Butterfly Garden, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Canoe Event with Junior Garden Club, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Carrie Cupp and Other Junior Garden Club Portraits, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Christmas Choir, Undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Christmas Party, 1996-2001 (Box 8, Folder 34-36)
  - Christmas Tea and Tour, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Civics, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Civics and Conservation, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Community Day, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Community Day, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Community Day, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Convention in Monroeville, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Convention, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 43b)
  - Costume Party, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Dan Gielas Eagle Award, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Day Lily Field Trip, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Dinner Event, Undated (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Display Planter, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 47b)
  - District VII Meeting, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Duff Park, 1997-1999 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Duff Park Mushroom Walk, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Earth Day and Arbor Day, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Easter Egg Decorating, undated (Box 8, Folder 51b)
  - Event at Marian Weihe's House, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Fashion Show, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - February Birdfeeders, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Field Trips, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary Celebration, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Flower Presentation Workshop, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Flower Sale, Undated (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Flower Show, 1984-2004 (Box 8, Folder 59-69)
  - Flower Show and Pumpkins, Undated (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Fruit Basket Raffle, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Convention, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania Food Sale, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Garden Club Party, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Garden Club Singing at Event, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Garden Club Therapy, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Garden Club Therapy, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Garden Tour, 1986-2012 (Box 9, Folder 8-11)
  - General Photographs, 1986-2015 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Gingerbread House Workshop, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Girl Scouts, c. 1970s and 1980s (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Greens Cutting, Undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Greens Cutting, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Greens Cutting, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Greens Sale, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Greens Sale, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Greens Workshop, 1984-1995 (Box 9, Folder 20-24)
  - Greensburg Garden Club President at Presidents Luncheon, Undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Greensburg Juniors Flower Basket Making Event, c. 1996 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Greensburg May Mart, 1994-1996 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Guest Speakers, 1986-2006 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - January Dried Floewr Arrangements Event, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Juanita Pattonson and Wanda Suarez, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - July Picnic, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - July Picnic, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - June Meeting, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Junior Garden Club Display at Horne's, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Junior Garden Club Events (Part I of II), Undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Junior Garden Club Events (Part II of II), Undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Junior Garden Club Events, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Junior Garden Club Field Trip to Beechwod Farms, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Junior Garden Club Field Trip to Duff Park, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Junior Garden Club Field Trip to Racoon State Park, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Junior Garden Club Flower Show, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Junior Garden Club Flower Show, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Junior Garden Club Flower Show, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Junior Garden Club General Photographs, Various (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Junior Garden Club Giving Mr. Benkert Teacher Award, c. 1980s (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Junior Garden Club Making Birdfeeders, Undated (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Junior Garden Club Mulch Making, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Junior Garden Club Nature Walk, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Junior Garden Club Outdoor Crafting, Undated (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Junior Garden Club Planting (June-August), 1990 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Junior Garden Club Planting at Frankling Regional, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Junior Garden Club Plant Potting Workshop, Undated (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Junior Garden Club Programming, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Junior Garden Club Wreath Making, Undated (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Library Civic Conservation, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 54b)
  - March Meeting, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - May Mart, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - May Program, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - May Program, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - May Show, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - May Workshop, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Municipal Park Rededication, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Murrysville Garden Club Newsletter, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - National Council of State Garden Clubs Grant, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - New Member Tea, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - November Junior Program, c. 1990s (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - November Meeting, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - November Meeting, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Nursing Homes - Arts and Crafts, c. 1990s (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Nursing Homes - General Photographs, Undated (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Nursing Homes - General Photographs, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Nursing Homes - Michael Nursing Home, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Nursing Homes - Murray Manor Garden Therapy, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Nursing Homes - Murray Manor, 1986-2006 (Box 9, Folder 73-77)
  - Nursing Homes - Murray Manor Pomanders and Pumpkins, Undated (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Nursing Homes - Murray Manor Sand Painting, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Nursing Homes - Portraits, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Nursing Homes - St. Patrick's Day Blarney Stones, Undated (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - October Event, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - October Meeting, Undated (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Ohio Flower Show and Junior Degenhardt Roses, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Orchid Program, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Outdoor Ship-Themed Event, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Painting Workshop, Undated (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Phipps Conservatory, Undated (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Plant Sale, 1963-2003 (Box 9, Folder 88b-94)
  - Plant and Flower Show, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Pond, House, and Animals, c. 1980s or 1990s (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Portraits, c. 1970s (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Portraits and Photographs of Members, 1982-2002 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Poster Contest, c. 1980s (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Presidents Appreciation Event (January), 1996 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - President's Luncheon, 1986-2005 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Projects, undated (Box 9, Folder 101b)
  - Rachel Carson House, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Railroad Garden Tour, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Rotary Garden, c. 1970s or 1980s (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Route 22 Beautification, 2012 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Sarah Duff, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - School Planting, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - Scholarship Winners, 1973-2001 (Box 9, Folder 107b-109)
  - Senior Flower Show, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - September District VII Meeting, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 111)
  - September Meeting, Undated (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - September Program, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Seven Springs Convention, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Silver Trophy, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - Sloan Elementary School Path Construction, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - Sloan Elementary School Tree and Herb Planting, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Speaker at Treehouse, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Spring Workshop, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - Top Junior Garden Club in Pennsylvania Celebration, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - Townsend Park Deceased Members Memorial Ceremony, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - Tree Planting, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 122)
  - Unidentified Award Winners, undated (Box 9, Folder 122b)
  - Unidentified Events on Polaroid, c. 1980s and 1990s (Box 9, Folder 123)
  - Unidentified Negatives, Various (Box 9, Folder 124)
  - Unidentified Photographs, Undated (Box 9, Folder 125-129)
  - Unidentiied Photographs, undated (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
  - War Memorials, 1986-2016 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Welcome to Murrysville Sign, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Wildlife Rehabilitation, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Workshops, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - WQED Studio, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Youth Activities, c. 1970s (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Youth Camping Trip, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Youth Event, c. 1980s (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Youth Flower Presentation Event, Undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Youth Fishing Project, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Youth Teaching Events, Undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Youth Wreath and Basket Making, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Audio-Visual Materials, XII.
  This series is composed of all audio-visual material in the collection. The records consist of VHS tapes and computer disks. The VHS tapes were originally used in awards applications. The computer disk contains soley audio, whereas the VHS tapes have moving image data. Most of the material is undated, but the computer disk is dated as a copy of a 1975 interview on tape. The items are organized by medium, with VHS tapes first followed by CDs second.
  - Awards--Jean Williams & Jane Dole, undated (Box 11, Video 1)
  - Murraysville Garden Club, "Video of Christmas Tour, Tea and Bazaar," [24.5 minutes], undated (Box 11, Video 2)
  - Anna Cotter Interviewed by Jeanne Daly, [19.59 minutes], 1975 (Box 11, Disc 1)
- Scrapbooks, 1957-1963; XIII.
  This series is composed four scrapbooks, which contain materials documenting Murrysville Garden Club activities from 1957-1997. The materials included in the scrapbooks are yearbooks, awards, flyers, prize ribbons, newspaper clippings, letters, programs, and photographs.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1957-1963 (Box 11, Volume 1)